# Morgan Mastrangelo

## Senior Front End Developer

™ mmastrangelo1120@gmail.com

**##** 1994-11-20

+1 727 300 2593

Saint Petersburg, FL

https://github.com/morgan-mastrangelo

https://www.hackerrank.com/mmastrangelo1120

https://discord.com/channels/1098706391377662076/1098706392099078145



#### ౭≡

#### **Profile**

As a highly-motivated senior front-end web developer with a passion for all stages of web design and development, excited to take on new challenges and utilize my skills and knowledge in programming languages to help the company achieve its goals with 7 years of project experience collaborate effectively with team members and project managers. What sets me apart, however, is my deep understanding of user experience (UX) and user interface (UI) design. As a specialist in creating intuitive and user-centered designs, I am able to provide a unique perspective that will improve the overall experience for your audience. Whether it's crafting a beautiful, one-of-akind web design or optimizing an existing interface, I am always eager to find new and innovative ways to elevate user engagement and take it by storm. With my combination of technical expertise and creative vision, I am confident that I would be a valuable asset to your team.



#### **Skills**

#### **Programming Languages**

C/C++, C#, Java, Python, Kotlin Go, Ruby, Rust, Perl, Swift, Matlab, Scala, HTML, CSS, SQL, XML, Javascript, Typescript, GraphQL

#### **Frontend Development**

ReactJS, Angular, AngularJS, VueJS, React Native, NextJS, NuxtJS, jQuery, Gatsby, AWS, iOS

#### **Database Management**

MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Oracle, SQLite, MariaDB

#### **Content Management System**

WordPress, Shopify, Sanity

#### **Web Design**

Photoshop, UX/UI, Emotional intelligence, Motion design, TailwindCSS, Material UI, SVG, Canvas

#### **Backend Development**

ExpressJS, NestJS, Ruby on Rails, PHP, Laravel, Django, ASP.NET, Spring boot, Flask, REST API

#### **Version Control & Project Management**

GitHub, Gitlab, GitBucket, SVN, Visual Source Safe

#### Education

#### Bachelor's in Advanced Computer Science,

Nova Southeasten University (NSU Florida)

2012 - 2016Fort Lauderdale, United States

### Professional Experience

#### **Freelancer**, Freelancer and Upwork

2016 - 2018

Saint Petersburg, FL, United States

- Built several desktop applications with C/C++, QML, and mobile applications using Java.
- Designed a search feature for an open-source visual programming tool to help users better navigate the system.
- Valued on project management expertise in front-end development.

#### Web Designer, Boston Consulting Group

2018 - 2019

San Francisco, CA, United States

- Designed Company Logo, Portfolio Blog, etc.
- Created high-quality and visually-appealing websites for small and medium-sized businesses according to their specific needs.

#### Frontend Web Developer, Uber Technologies

2019 - 2022

San Francisco, CA, United States

- Used Javascript, HTML, and CSS to develop web applications for various industries.
- Developed a booking application using React, Next.js, and Node.js to let users book a service online and get real-time updates on their progress.
- Developed a web interface using Vue to perform CRUD operations on tasks with large files, driving up the performance of a workflow pipeline by 60%.
- Created a mobile responsive web design for an online store that gets 65% of its traffic from mobiles
- Developed and maintained web applications using Django, AngularJS, and MySQL.
- Followed a Kanban-style workflow using Trello boards
- Worked with back-end, front-end, and full-stack developers to achieve client objectives.

#### Senior Front End Developer, Pfizer

2022 - Present

New York, NY, United States

- Taught 7 junior front-end developers and utilized their technical skills to achieve the organization's objectives.
- Converted given wireframes into Vue components and designed a mobile-friendly UI to provide a better user experience across multiple devices.
- Collaborated and managed teams in web application development, such as E-commerce, and social websites.
- Improved the home page views from 1.5K to 150K weekly through SEO optimization, A/B testing, and conversion rate optimization.
- Reduced development time by 75% through code reuse in JQuery libraries for various projects with over 5.4K combined page visits.